Malcolm S. Knowles Papers
Malcolm S. Knowles Papers
- Printed material
  - Evaluation guide for college women's re-entry programs, by Jack Mezirow and Amy D. Rose, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Evaluation forms (Box 35)
  - Evaluation of adult and continuing education, 1971-1985 (Box 35)
  - Exchange: organizational behavior teaching journal, vol. 8, no. 3, 4, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Expanded food and nutrition education program (EFNEP)...accomplishments and future needs, by Nancy B. Leidenfrost, 1975 (Box 35)
  - Experiment with group self-directed learning: learning-teaching team, by Malcolm S. Knowles, undated (Box 35)
  - Experiment with the teacher-learning team: group self-directed learning in undergraduate education, by Eugene E. DuBois, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Explorations: human relations training and research, no. 1, 2, 1967 (Box 35)
  - Facilities for study in the arts in Canada, by Canadian Cultural Information Centre, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Factors associated with the achievement of adult students, by King M. Wientge and Philip H. DuBois, 1964 (Box 35)
  - Federal activities in support of adult education, by National Advisory Council on Adult Education, 1972 (Box 35)
  - Federal support for adult education: directory of programs and services, 1966 (Box 36)
  - Field of operations in adult education, by Malcolm S. Knowles, undated (Box 36)
  - Financing adult education in selected schools and community colleges, by Homer Kempfer and William R. Wood, 1952 (Box 36)
  - Florida State University - Department of Adult Education proposal, 1969 (Box 36)
  - La formation aux U.S.A.: résultats d'un voyage effectué par la CEGOS, by Henri Fraisse, circa 1979 (Box 36)
  - Formation of the learning community, by Sunny Robinson, 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Foxmoor Casual Retail Stores field management development program, 1978 (Box 36)
  - General theory of the doctorate in education and a special theory of the Ed.D. with a specialization in adult education, by Malcolm S. Knowles, undated (Box 36)
  - Gifted underachievers: follow-up study of four types of treatment, by Thomas J. Mallinson, 1964 (Box 36)
  - Girl Scouts of the United States of America, 1969; leadership workbooks (Box 36)
  - Group home project: exploration into the use of group homes for delinquents in a differential treatment setting, by John W. Pearson, 1970 (Box 36)
  - Group services in public welfare: guides for administration and program development, by Harleigh B. Trecker, 1964 (Box 36)
  - Guide to studies in adult education 1966-1967, compiled by C.D. Legge, circa 1967 (Box 36)
  - Guidelines for contributors to adult education, 4th ed., 1970 (Box 36)
  - Guidelines for the proposal writer, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Guidelines for the volunteer coordinator, by Betty H. Wiser and Emerson H. Snipes, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Harvard University Medical School, Department of Psychiatry, 1969; laboratory of community psychiatry (Box 36)
  - How to assess the needs of community instructional services, by George F. Aker and Richard W. Kemerer, 1980 (Box 36)
  - How to close the gap in human performance, by James F. Bolt and Geary A. Rummler, 1982 (Box 36)
  - Humanistic education and human services network newsletter, 1984 (Box 36)
  - I can: volunteer development workbook, by American Red Cross, undated (Box 36)
  - It happens when we get there: conversations with teachers in Alaskan village, by David Beers, 1978 (Box 36)
  - Identification of program priorities in continuing dental education, 1978 (Box 36)
  - Improving teaching effectiveness, 1970 (Box 37)
  - Informal paper for Dr. Malcolm Knowles, by Donald R. McNeil, 1967 (Box 37)
  - Institute for Strategic Studies, Community development bulletin, vol. 2, no. 1, 1965 (Box 37)
  - Interchange, vol. 3, no. 1, 1972 (Box 37)
  - International Congress of University Adult Education (ICUAE)
    - ICUAE Journal, 1968; 1969,; 1970,; 1971,; 1972,; vol. 7, no. 2, 3; vol. 8, no. 1; vol. 9, nos. 1, 3; vol. 10, nos. 1-3; vol. 11, no. 1/2; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - ICUAE Newsletter, 1963; 1968-1969; nos. 3, 8, 9 (Box 37)
  - International educational and cultural exchange, vol. 4, no. 1-3, 1968-1969 (Box 37)
  - International journal of career and continuing education, vol. 1, no. 1, 1975 (Box 37)
  - International journal of continuing education and training, vol. 3, no. 3/4, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Interscholastic athletic administration, vol. 3, no. 1, 1976 (Box 37)
  - Japan Council of Social Education. On the promotion of university extension, by Shunsaku Kawahara, 1964 (Box 37)
  - Job competence assessment: defining the attributes of the top performer, by George O. Klemp, Jr., 1982 (Box 37)
  - Johns Hopkins University Evening College
    - Assessing experiential learning and professional change agentry educational needs, 1975 (Box 37)
    - Community competencies and concepts: outcomes of a study to determine training needs of community change agents, undated (Box 38)
    - Final evaluation of community change competencies, 1974 (Box 38)
    - Hopkins fellows in organizational and community systems proposal, 1975 (Box 38)
    - Nocturne, vol. 1, no. 1, 1973 (Box 38)
  - Journal of process design proposed plan, 1971 (Box 38)
  - Journal of voluntary action research, 1976; 1977; vol. 5, no. 2; vol. 6, no. 3-4; Indices (Box 38)
  - Kenya journal of adult education, vol. 3, no. 2, 1974 (Box 38)
  - Leadership Resources, Inc. Program for Supervisors of Disadvantaged Employees, Resource person's guide, 1968 (Box 38)
  - Leadership training program for selected African health specialists, by H. Curtis Mial, 1966 (Box 38)
  - Learning connection, vol. 1, no. 1, 1980 (Box 38)
  - Learning environment and adult education papers, undated (Box 38)
  - Learning for living reports, 1961 (Box 38)
  - Learning in an open society: credit for experience, ed. by Robert J. Barak and Roger S. McCannon, 1975 (Box 38)
  - Learning opportunities for adults: literature review, vol. 1, by JoAn S. Segal, 1977 (Box 38)
  - Let's teach adults, prepared by a group of adult educators, 1954 (Box 38)
  - Life Office Management Association, 1972-1973; education pamphlets (Box 38)
  - Life planning for women, by Kitty Hunter, undated (Box 38)
  - Lifelong education and the school: abstracts and bibliography, by R.H. Dave and N. Stiemerling, 1973 (Box 39)
  - Life-span developmental psychology, by Louise A. Casey, 1974 (Box 39)
  - List of institutions and individuals active in university adult education, by International Congress of University Adult Education, undated (Box 39)
  - Malvern learning exchange, 1978 (Box 39)
  - Managerial behavior and participation in a laboratory training process, by Fred I. Steele, Dale E. Zand and Sheldon S. Zalkind, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Managerial learning laboratory: changes in values and performance during and after training, by Ernest M. Schuttenberg, 1968 (Box 39)
  - Mandatory continuing education for professional nurse relicensure: what are the issues, by Barbara J. Stevens, 1973 (Box 39)
  - Massachusetts Association of Public School Adult Educators, Contact, vol. 4, no. 3, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Matthew Paris, medieval chronicler and historian, 1934; honors thesis by Malcolm S. Knowles (Box 39)
  - McBer and Company, Institute for Competency Assessment
    - Competency reports and papers (Box 39)
    - Higher education consortium on assessment, 1977 (Box 39)
    - Test materials, 1976 (Box 39)
  - McGraw-Hill catalogs, 1977 (Box 39)
  - Medical Television Network Educational Program, Life cycle, undated (Box 39)
  - Methodology for describing federal programs that support adult learning opportunities, by G. Roger Sell and JoAn S. Segal, 1977 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous adult education papers (Box 39)
  - Missouri Adult Education Association, Inc., News exchange, vol. 1, no. 3, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Model (based upon open systems organizational theory) for continuing educational needs assessment in continuing professional education programs, by Paul E. Masmanian (Box 40)
  - Model for program planning in adult education, by James R. LaForest, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Model of group adaptation to organizational change in communication networks, by Arthur M. Cohen, 1965 (Box 40)
  - Models and ideas about changing, by Robert Chin, 1963 (Box 40)
  - Modern practice of adult education
    - Notes and outlines, undated (Box 40)
    - Reviews, 1970-1972 (Box 40)
  - Mountain Plains Adult Education Association, Journal of adult education, vol. 11, no. 1, 2, 1982-1983 (Box 40)
  - National Academy for Health Inservice Education
    - Inservice ideas, vol. 1, no. 1, 1971 (Box 40)
    - Inservice education: most promising manpower resources is the manpower that's already there, 1970 (Box 40)
  - National Advisory Council for Career Education, 1977; career education publications (Box 40)
  - National Association for Mental Health, Design for staff development, by Kathryn Oliphant, 1973 (Box 40)
  - National Association of Professors of Continuing and Adult Education (NAPCAE), Administrators swap shop, vol. 16, no. 6, 1975 (Box 40)
  - National Board on Graduate Education final report, 1975 (Box 40)
  - National Center for Educational Brokering publications (Box 40)
  - National Clearinghouse for Alcohol Information of the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, 1973; alcohol and health notes (Box 40)
  - National Council on Adult Education, 1977; working party on training of continuing educators report (Box 40)
  - National Education Finance Project special study, 1970 (Box 40)
  - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) Division of Manpower and Training Programs, Continuing Education Grants Program
    - Guides and checklists for site visits, 1971-1972 (Box 40)
    - Objectives, priorities and guidelines, 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - National Laboratory for Higher Education, 1970 (Box 40)
  - National longitudinal study of the high school class of 1972
    - Capsule description of first follow-up survey data, 1976 (Box 40)
    - Changes in attitudes one and one-half years after graduation, 1975 (Box 40)
    - Comparative profiles one and one-half years after graduation, 1975 (Box 40)
  - National organizations and voluntary associations with adult education concerns in the United States, 1971 (Box 40)
  - National Security Affairs monograph series, no. 8, 1980 (Box 40)
  - National Student Nurses Association, Imprint, vol. 18, no. 1, 1971 (Box 40)
  - National Technical Assistance Consortium for Two-Year Colleges, Acction quarterly review, vol. 4, no. 2, 1978 (Box 40)
  - National Training and Development Service, National news, vol. 3, no. 4, 1975 (Box 40)
  - National University Extension Association (NUEA), NUEA newsletter, vol. 5, no. 22, 1972 (Box 40)
  - New career models for future psychiatrists, by Raquel E. Cohen, M.D., undated (Box 41)
  - New Jersey State Department of Health, Alcohol Education Resource Unit, undated (Box 41)
  - New Tools for Learning, Guide to films, pamphlets and recordings for teachers, speakers and discussion leaders, 1943 (Box 41)
  - New York State
    - Board of Regents Commission on Doctoral Education, Meeting the needs of doctoral education in New York State, 1973 (Box 41)
    - Education Department Rating Committee, Office of Doctoral Project Report and recommendations to commissioner of education, 1979-1980 (Box 41)
    - Education Department Rating Committee, Study of adult education, 1974-1976 (Box 41)
  - News journal, 1978 (Box 41)
  - NM [New management], vol. 1, no. 3, 1984 (Box 41)
  - No-nonsense communication supplement, by Donald L. Kirkpatrick, undated (Box 41)
  - Non-credit activities in institutions of higher education for the year ending June 30 1976, by Florence B. Kemp, 1978 (Box 41)
  - Non-degree research in adult education in Canada, 1968 (Box 41)
  - North Carolina Educational Information Centers, Explore, 1981 (Box 41)
  - North Carolina State University
    - Agricultural Experiment Station, Technical bulletin no. 248, 249, 1976 (Box 41)
    - Agricultural Extension Service, Extension news, vol. 61, no 1, 1974 (Box 41)
    - Alumni Association, NCSU alumni news, vol. 47, no. 2, 1974 (Box 41)
    - Department of Adult and Community College Education, Bibliography of doctoral dissertations, 1967-1974 (Box 41)
    - Department of Adult and Community College Education, Master bibliography, ed. by Malcolm S. Knowles, 1977-1978 (Box 41)
    - Urban Affairs Center, Center policy on staff development, by Jack Fritz, undated (Box 41)
  - North Carolina: Today and tomorrow, by James A. Christenson, 1975-1976 (Box 41)
  - Northwest Adult Education Association, NWAEA notes, no. 7, 1970 (Box 41)
  - Nursing digest, 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - Observation process for decision making, undated (Box 41)
  - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education (OISE)
    - Department of Adult Education, Renewal, 1970 (Box 41)
    - Report, 1968 (Box 41)
  - Organization of community groups in support of the planning process and code enforcement administration, by Robert E. Knittel, Ph.D., 1970 (Box 41)
  - Organizational development: fantasy or reality, by Leslie E. This, 1969 (Box 41)
  - Overview and history of the field, by Cyril O. Houle, 1957 (Box 41)
  - Overview of adult education research proposal, 1979 (Box 41)
  - Panhandle Area Educational Cooperative, undated; teacher education module catalog (Box 41)
  - Paradoxes in research administration, by Warren C. Lathrop, 1959 (Box 41)
  - Parent education- curriculums, methods and materials, by Milton Babitz, 1961 (Box 41)
  - Participants in postsecondary education: October, 1982; 1984 (Box 42)
  - Participation in adult education, 1971; 1974; initial report and final report; 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Participation in adult education, by Marie D. Wann and Marthine V. Woodward, 1959 (Box 42)
  - Pennsylvania adult education project, 1984 (Box 42)
  - Performance-based teacher education series, no. 1, 8, 10, 1971-1973 (Box 42)
  - Personal statement about learning theory, by John Ohliger, 1974 (Box 42)
  - Personality characteristics and learning style preferences of adult basic education students, by Anthony V. Manzo, Mary Lorton and Frank W.F. Condon, 1975 (Box 42)
  - Perspectives in adult learning and development, vol. 4, no. 1, 1982-1983 (Box 42)
  - Phases of community action, 1953 (Box 42)
  - Phi Delta Kappa proposal, 1974 (Box 42)
  - Planned change in higher education, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Policy Research Incorporated, Problem definition and solution strategies in dental practice, 1980 (Box 42)
  - Poorer nations failing to cut education gap, by M.A. Farber, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Prairie View Mental Health Center, 1972; training grant application (Box 42)
  - Prasar, 1974-1975; 1975-1976,; 1976-1977; vol. 2 nos. 1-4; vol. 3 nos. 1, 4; vol. 4 nos. 2-4; 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Presbyterian School of Christian Education, 1985; strategic plan (Box 42)
  - Present status of the field (chapter 2), by Malcolm S. Knowles, undated (Box 42)
  - President Silber: making BU safe for the rich, by Jon Harris, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Probabilistic functionalism: conception of research method, by Lewis Petrinovich, 1979 (Box 42)
  - Problem-solving model in continuing education for dental practitioners, by Laurette F. Lipson, M.N.Ed., Kenneth D. Keith, Ph.D. and Gary L. Jones, M.S., D.D.S., undated (Box 42)
  - Proposal to establish a department of community college and continuing education in the Boston University School of Education, 1973 (Box 43)
  - Proposal to establish the State University of Nebraska, 1971 (Box 43)
  - Proposal to the W.K. Kellogg Foundation organizing a national campaign to strengthen adult learning, 1983 (Box 43)
  - Psychological test specialists information and order forms, undated (Box 43)
  - Pulse, vol. 7, no. 1, 1966 (Box 43)
  - Professional Exchange Program, 1969-1970; data and survey results; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Programs and registrations 1974-1975 joint report by Association of Continuing Higher Education and National University Extension Association (Box 43)
  - Projections of educational statistics to 1982-1983 (Box 43)
  - Projections of educational statistics to 1984-1985 (Box 43)
  - Questionnaire about adult education participant attitudes, undated (Box 43)
  - Reaching adults for lifelong learning, 1972; 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Recent federal laws related to adult education, undated (Box 43)
  - Recurrent education: strategy for lifelong learning, chapter 1, 1973 (Box 43)
  - Relationship between college grades and adult achievement, by Donald P. Hoyt, 1965 (Box 43)
  - Relationship between the elementary age child's self-concept and his academic and social functioning, by Robert Morgan, undated (Box 43)
  - Report on education research, vol. 5, no. 3, 1973 (Box 43)
  - Report to the Adult Education Association, by Edmund des Brunner, 1959 (Box 43)
  - Research and investigations in adult education, 1968; 1971; annual registers (Box 43)
  - Research and investigations in adult education, 1972; annual registers (Box 44)
  - Research and training opportunities abroad: 1972-1973 higher education programs in foreign language and area studies, 1971 (Box 44)
  - Research currents, 1973 (Box 44)
  - Research highlights in aging, 1961 (Box 44)
  - Research in instructional television and film, by J. Christopher Reid and Donald W. MacLennan, 1967 (Box 44)
  - Research needs in adult education, by Henry G. Brady, Ph.D., 1982 (Box 44)
  - Research projects of adult education professors, undated (Box 44)
  - Research related to adult education conducted at the University of British Columbia, by Gary Dickinson, 1968 (Box 44)
  - Residential colleges: some new developments in British adult education, by Guy Hunter, undated (Box 44)
  - Resources for change: guide to projects 1975-1976, by Fund for Improvement of Post-Secondary Education (Box 44)
  - Resources for developing volunteer programs: annotated bibliography, by Betty H. Wiser, 1971 (Box 44)
  - Resources for educators of adults, 1978 (Box 44)
  - ROCOM (Division of Hoffman-La Roche Inc.) / American College of Physicians, Medical skills library, 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - Role and training of adult educators in Czechoslovakia, by Jindra Kulich, 1967 (Box 44)
  - Safeguarding democracy through adult civic education, by J.W. Studebaker, 1938 (Box 44)
  - Selected approaches to adult education, by Homer Kempfer and Grace S. Wright, 1950 (Box 44)
  - Selected higher education publications, 1974 (Box 44)
  - Self-evaluation model for non-degree special purpose schools for working adults, by Edmund N. Fulker, 1968 (Box 44)
  - Serious case for silliness, by Marlowe O. Erickson, 1984 (Box 45)
  - Skeleton strategy of the development of a system of polyvalent curricula for the entire educational system, by Gustav Thuro, 1977 (Box 45)
  - Small business management series nos. 7, 12, 1953; 1955 (Box 45)
  - Social education in Japan, 1967 (Box 45)
  - Social physics and the effects of others research proposal, by Eric S. Knowles, 1977 (Box 45)
  - Some comments regarding research based on questionnaires and interviews, by Ralph M. Stodgill (Box 45)
  - Some guidelines for the preparation of dissertation proposals, by Malcolm S. Knowles, undated (Box 45)
  - Some papers, research reports and experiments on andragogy: bibliography, by Malcolm S. Knowles, 1979 (Box 45)
  - Some psychological dimensions of life long learning, by Howard McCluskey, 1975-1976 (Box 45)
  - Sources of information on educational media, by John A. Molstad, 1963 (Box 45)
  - Southern Regional Education Board
    - Physicians' digest for continuing psychiatric education programs, 1-16, 1970-1973 (Box 45)
    - Policies in a state mental health agency, 1974 (Box 45)
  - Staff development and continuing education programs for library personnel, by Barbara Conroy, 1974 (Box 45)
  - Staff development and practice supervision, by Joanne I. Bell, undated (Box 45)
  - Staff development pamphlets and reports (Box 45)
  - Staff development reports, papers and pamphlets, 1974-1980 (Box 45)
  - Staff development: supervisor's job, 1963 (Box 45)
  - Staff training reports (Box 45)
  - State staff members for adult basic education programs directory, 1965 (Box 45)
  - State University of New York (SUNY) at Albany
    - Component, undated (Box 45)
    - Component AE 02.000, undated (Box 46)
    - Component AE 04.000, undated (Box 46)
  - Statistics of public school adult education 1958-1959, by Marthine V. Woodward, 1961 (Box 46)
  - Stouffer Hotels, Department of Organization Development, LCI sales management training program, 1978 (Box 46)
  - Strategies of research on learning in educational settings, by Philip H. DuBois and King M. Wientge, 1964 (Box 46)
  - Studiecirkel ledaren, by Sven-Arne Stahre, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Studies and training in continuing education: directory of residential continuing education centers in the United States and Canada, 1963-1964 (Box 46)
  - Studies in adult education, vol. 1, no. 2, 1969 (Box 46)
  - Study of factors influencing the continuing education of law enforcement officers, by Jay L. Chronister, Bruce M. Gansneder, John C. LeDouk, and Edward J. Tully, 1982 (Box 46)
  - Study of the persistence of adult students in the fundamental learning laboratories of the North Carolina community college system, by William David Killian, 1969 (Box 46)
  - Successful industrial innovations, by Sumner Myers and Donald G. Marquis, 1969 (Box 46)
  - Supplementary knowledge of results, by E. Maltzman, W.C. Holz and Jean Kunze, 1965 (Box 46)
  - Survey of graduate programs in adult education in the United States and Canada, 1968; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Survey of the current situation in higher adult education in the United States, by Robert J. Pitchell, undated (Box 46)
  - Sweden, Department of Educational Research, Sos-vux project, circa 1970's (Box 46)
  - Synectics education systems, catalogs and journal articles (Box 47)
  - Syracuse University, Final report on Ed.D. and Ph.D. in adult education, by New York State Education Department Office of Doctoral Projects Rating Committee, 1979 (Box 47)
  - Tale of three cities: Elsinore-Montreal-Tokyo, by James Robbins Kidd, 1974 (Box 47)
  - Talent and tomorrow's teachers, by Lanora G. Lewis, J. Ned Bryan and Robert Poppendieck, 1963 (Box 47)
  - Teacher influence, pupil attitudes and achievement, by Ned A. Flanders, 1965 (Box 47)
  - Team building for matrix organizations, by Dr. Gordon L. Lippitt, 1969 (Box 47)
  - Techniques and criteria for designing and selecting instruments for assessing teachers, by Paul S. Pottinger, undated (Box 47)
  - Testing and grading articles, booklets and papers, 1973-1977 (Box 47)
  - Tourism as cultural learning, by Midori Matsuyama and Theodore Brameld, 1976 (Box 47)
  - Toward a social-industrial complex, by Simon Ramo, 1972 (Box 47)
  - Trainer competency questionnaire, 1981 (Box 47)
  - Tribute to Lee Bradford, undated (Box 47)
  - Triton Corporation, Continuing education: state programs for the 70's, 1969 (Box 47)
  - Union Graduate School newsletter, vol. 5, no. 3, 1975 (Box 47)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)
    - Education abstracts, vol. 11, no. 8; vol. 12, nos. 4-6, 1959; 1960 (Box 47)
    - Recommendation on the development of adult education, 1976 (Box 47)
  - United States Civil Service Commission
    - Atlanta Regional Training Center, undated; interagency training curricula (Box 47)
    - Atlanta Regional Training Center, Train, vol. 1, no. 1, 1978 (Box 47)
    - Bureau of Training, Employee training in the federal service, 1972 (Box 47)
    - Training policies for various agencies, 1962 (Box 47)
  - United States Department of Agriculture Extension Service, 1975-1977; staff development reports and pamphlets (Box 47)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW)
    - National Institute of Education, 1977; entitlement papers (Box 47)
    - National Institute of Education, 1979; request for proposals (Box 48)